# CHAD PIOTROVSKY

Auburn Hills, MI 48326 ♦ Phone: 248-396-7490 ♦ Email: <a href="mailto:cpiotrovsky@att.net">cpiotrovsky@att.net</a> ♦ GitHub:

https://github.com/C3-PIO ♦ LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/chadpiotrovsky

## **Professional Summary**

Adaptable Software Engineer with experience in Object Oriented Programming, SDLC, agile project management, and full stack application development. Understanding of non-relational databases, and state management. Possess strong problem-solving abilities, a passion for continued learning, excellent attention to detail, and elite interpersonal communication skills.

### **Technical Skills**

**Languages:** HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript **Front-End:** Next.js, React.js, Bootstrap

Back-End: MongoDB, Express.js, Node.js, JSON

Other: Object-Oriented Programming, RESTful API's, Git, Bash

## Certifications

Certificate of Completion: Software Engineering Bootcamp

June 2023
FHA Direct Endorsement

Jan. 2022

## **Project Experience**

#### Professional:

Bolt (Automated Underwriting System for UWM)

Sep. 2021-Feb. 2022

- Worked alongside developers to construct a user-friendly automated underwriting system
- Assisted with implementation of key system knowledge through extensive experience with previous underwriting operating systems and underwriting guidance

#### Personal:

- Personal Website (in progress):
  - Creating a stylish and dynamic personalized website using React to showcase projects, achievements, experience, and provide a summary of myself and goals
- Simon Game: Site <a href="https://c3-pio.github.io/Simon-Game/">https://c3-pio.github.io/Simon-Game/</a> Code <a href="https://github.com/C3-PIO/Simon-Game">https://github.com/C3-PIO/Simon-Game</a>
  - Designed a dynamic, fully functional memory game based on the light up Simon game I played as a kid. The game utilizes mainly javascript functionality to exhibit timed intervals, sequence playbacks, a game reset option, and multiple difficulty levels
  - Technologies: HTML, CSS, Vanilla JavaScript
- Music App: Site <a href="https://music-hl0j35him-c3-pio.vercel.app/">https://github.com/C3-PIO/Music-App</a>
  - Developed a fully responsive single page mock music app that utilizes web tokens and Spotify API JSON data to deliver and display personalized album, artist, playlist, and audiobook searches for the user
  - **Technologies**: React, Spotify API, JSX, Bootstrap, JSON

- To-Do App: Site <a href="https://to-do-app-lyxw.onrender.com/">https://github.com/C3-PIO/ToDoList</a> <a href="https://github.com/C3-PIO/ToDoListBE">https://github.com/C3-PIO/ToDoListBE</a>
  - Created a full stack to-do list creator that incorporates on the front-end with on the back-end that allows the user to create, track, and delete items on their to-do list
  - **Technologies:** MERN Stack, Axios

## **Education**

Per Scholas, Detroit, MI

Feb. 2023- June 2023

**Full Stack Development Bootcamp**: 600+ hours of intensive hands-on training in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Git, and the MERN stack.

- Developed more than 50 dynamic web applications using front-end technologies such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ReactJS, and Redux, as well as back-end technologies such as Node.js, Mongoose, MongoDB, and ExpressJS both individually and as a part of agile teams.
- Skilled in agile project management, SDLC, OOP best practices, and algorithmic coding challenges

**Oakland University**, Rochester Hills, MI *Bachelor of Science*, Health Sciences

April 2016

# **Work Experience**

## Senior Underwriting Team Lead

United Wholesale & Equity Prime Mortgage

Oct. 2017-Dec. 2022

- Managed a team of 12-15 colleagues; assisted with guideline application and understanding, organized meetings for personal and professional growth, and led weekly trainings and projects to improve individual and group performance
- Maintained elite loan quality and production standards for the team and myself to achieve top individual and team rankings within the company each month
- Provided excellent client service to all involved in the loan process: both internally and externally to ensure continued client satisfaction

### **Key Team Lead: Department Coordinator**

**Dunhams Athleisure Corporation** 

July 2014-Oct. 2017

- Led all operations involving receipt of product and product merchandising to ensure practical organization and presentation of the store products
- Performed all tasks related to proper opening of the store: balanced cash drawers, emailed daily sales and hours information, and created schedules for proper coverage
- Consulted with customers to evaluate desired products, assist with questions, and provide recommendations when necessary to achieve elite customer satisfaction